[Music]
Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine
and today we're talking a
little bit about, well,
kind of girly things.
That's right, we've talked about
guys, shoes, women's shoes.
So now we're going to
talk about another aspect
of women's accessories. We're
going to talk about makeup.
Okay, so we're
wearing makeup today.
Actually, we're buying
makeup at the store.
I never even knew there
were so many kinds of
makeup, so we're going to learn
all about these in today's dialog.
I'm hungry. Let's go grab a bite to eat.
Yeah, me too.
Oh, can we stop at the shop really fast?
I lost my makeup back at the airport
and I want to pick up a few things.
Will you take long?
No, five minutes, I promise.
Come on, we've been
here for almost an hour.
I thought you said you're
only going to get a few things.
How long does it take you to pick
out a lipstick and some nail polish?
Are you crazy?
You have no idea what you're talking about.
Just for my eyes, I
have to get eyeliner and
eyelash curler, eyeshadow
and eyebrow pencil and mascara.
Then I need to get
foundation, liquid foundation.
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Are you nuts?
How much is all this going to cost?
I'm looking at the price of each one
of these little things and it's outrageous.
This is basically a crayon. What about you?
You spend as much money or more on your
razors after shave,
cologne and gel.
Not to mention how much you spend on clothes
and... Fine, get the stupid $30 crayon.
All right, we're back. So
obviously we're getting
a lot of things for this
girl, a lot of makeup.
So I think there are a couple of
things that we may not know about.
So let's take a look at them
now on the language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
So the first thing we're
talking about today is a basic,
most women carry this around
in their purses. It's called lipstick.
That's right. And
as you said, this is a
pretty basic thing. It's
the kind of like paint
that you put on your
lips and it's called a
lipstick because it
looks like a little stick.
Right, and you turn it with your fingers
and it comes up and then you turn it again
and it goes down basically keeping it
from touching all the things in your purse.
That's right. So lipstick.
And well, apart from
this, we also have nail
polish and this is also very
popular with the ladies when
you paint your nails a certain color.
That's right. So polish is basically
anything that makes something shiny.
It's something that
you add to surfaces.
So you could add
polish to wood on a table.
But in this case, we're
putting it on our nails.
That is fingernails or
toenails. So it's nail polish.
All right, very good. And
now we're getting into
the specific things. A lot
of makeup that women
use on their eyes. So
for example, the first
thing she said, she
needs to get an eyeliner.
Okay, so eyeliner
is basically a pencil.
This is what the guy is making
fun of her about. He says,
it's just a pencil or a
crayon for your eye.
And so basically you use
it to draw a line on the top
or the bottom of
your eye, your eyelid.
Okay, so yeah, it kind of
looks like a marker and it comes
I think black in
different colors.
And then you paint little
lines around your eyes to make
them more pronounced.
So it's called an eyeliner.
Okay, and now we
have an eyelash color.
And also, I think this is
very important for the ladies.
Yeah, well, not everyone
uses this. It's a little
bit of a scary instrument.
It looks like it might
pop your eye out. It's something
you use on your eyelashes.
So those are the
hairs that come off
of your eye and basically
basically you use this
to make them curly or to make them seem
a bit longer and prettier. So an eyelash
curler is something
that it's like a almost
like a press or something
for your eyelashes.
Okay, very good. And
well, now that we've got that
covered, we move
on to eye shadow.
And I think this goes on
your eyelid, right? That's right.
Some people make it go
further. They put it on their
face above their eyelid,
but that's a little bit crazy.
And I shadow generally goes
like you said on your eyelid.
And it can be in
many different colors.
So blue, pink, red,
whatever. People sometimes
go crazy with eyeshadow.
Okay. And now what about
an eyebrow pencil? This
is basically a pencil for
filling in or for
coloring your eyebrows.
Sometimes people like to make
their eyebrows look darker or thicker.
And so they use this pencil.
It's usually brown or black.
And they use it on their eyebrows.
So we've picked
up a lot of a vocab.
You're related to your eye. For
example, an eyelash, your eyelid.
Now we're talking about the eyebrows,
which are the hairs on top more or less
around your forehead. And
now we also have another
type of makeup called
mascara. This is another basic.
So like we said
earlier, lipstick is
something you almost
always find in a woman's purse.
Well, mascara is another
one of those things.
Almost everybody wears
mascara. This is kind of like a
brush for your eyelashes.
And it paints them a
different color. So most of
them wear black or brown.
And it makes your
eyelashes look really long.
Okay. Very good. So this is kind of like
paint for your eyelashes. And now moving
away from your eyelashes,
we're going to have
we're buying also some
foundation and liquid foundation.
Okay. So foundation
is just a kind of
base for your face. So
foundation like a building
is the very bottom.
Well, in this case, it's
something that you put
on your cheeks, on your
face in general, on your
forehead to kind of smooth
your skin out and make
it look all the same color
or the same, the same
texture. And so foundation
can be like, like we see
here, either a powder,
which is kind of like a dry
substance or you can use
liquid foundation,
which is like it says liquid.
It's almost like a thick
cream. All right. So foundation
is, as you said, I guess
you just want to make
your skin look the same
color, the same texture,
because obviously not
everyone's skin is perfect.
We don't have some spots
maybe or some different
color on our face. You say
we like you wear foundation
too, do you or makeup
marker? Well, I mean, we
as people, because you
know, all right, no, no, no,
none of this makeup for
me, although I have used
an eyelash curler
once. That's scary.
Well, my friends dared me
to. So okay. And you loved it.
Of course. Now I use
it all the time. No, no.
But what I do use is now
things related to guys.
So for example, the
girlfriend was saying, well,
you buy razors and aftershaves.
So what are these things?
Well, razors aren't
just a guy thing.
Everyone can have a razor.
It's basically a blade like
a very sharp piece of metal
that you use to cut hair.
So the hair on your
legs, the hair on your face,
these are these are things
that you cut with a razor.
And that menus razors
to shave their faces,
shave their chins or
above their lip. All right.
And well, actually, after
we shave our beard,
we put on a little bit
of aftershave, which is
basically kind of like
alcohol that smells really nice.
That's right. Because
shaving can actually hurt
your skin or the hairs
under your skin can become
really itchy or irritated.
And so aftershave
helps make everything
feel better. Okay.
And well, in sometimes we also
use a little bit of cologne to smell nice.
So women usually wear perfume, which
is, you know, the perfumes like CK and Ugo
boss and all that stuff,
as well as for guys,
it's usually called
cologne. Okay. That's right.
It's an important
difference there because we
don't say perfume for
guys. And we don't say
cologne for girls. So
women wear perfume like you
said, but men wear cologne.
And this word is very funny looking.
It ends with, it's
spelled C-O-L-O-G-N-E.
So you don't really say
the G. It's not cologna.
Right. It's cologne. And
it's something that you
put on your neck or
your face smell really good
if you're a man. Exactly.
And finally, if you have
long hair or maybe you
have very spiky hair like
I do, you need to
wear a little bit of gel to
kind of give your head
a little bit of shape.
That's right. So gel is actually
the name of a kind of substance.
It's not liquid, but
it's not hard either.
And it basically thick like paste that you
put in your hair to keep it in one place.
Yeah, it makes your
hair become a little bit
harder or it keeps your
hairstyle for a long time.
That's right. All right.
So a lot of vocab here,
a lot of things that
we've picked up.
Why don't we go back, review
all this great vocab on our
dialogue for today. I'm hungry.
Let's go grab a bite to eat.
Yeah, me too. Oh, can we stop at the shop
really fast? I lost my makeup bag at the
airport and I want to
pick up a few things.
Will you take long? No.
Five minutes. I promise.
Come on. We've been
here for almost an hour.
I thought you said you're
only going to get a few things.
How long does it take you to pick
out a lipstick and some nail polish?
Are you crazy? You have no
idea what you're talking about.
Just for my eyes, I
have to get eyeliner and
eyelash curler, eyeshadow, an
eyebrow pencil, and mascara.
Then I need to get foundation, liquid
foundation. Whoa, whoa, whoa. Are you nuts?
How much is all
this going to cost?
I'm looking at the price of
each one of these little things
and it's outrageous.
This is basically a crann.
What about you? You
spend as much money
you're more on your razors
after shave, cologne, and gel.
Not to mention how much
you spend on clothes and.
.. Fine. Get this
stupid $30 crann.
All right, we're back. So
now we're going to take
a look at three short
phrases that we've picked
out for you on fluency
builder. Fluency builder.
So this first phrase is
something that we always
almost always say with
our friends, our family.
When we're hungry,
we're shopping, you know,
sometimes you're outside
and you just really want to eat.
You say, "Hey, let's
grab a bite to eat.
" That's right. So this is
a very natural colloquial
way of saying, "Let's
go get something to eat.
Let's go eat something."
So it could be small.
It could be a snack like a ice cream, but
it can also be dinner. So hey, do you want
to go grab a bite
to eat sometimes?
That means, "Hey, do you want to
go have lunch or dinner sometime?
" Very good. So the
phrase is, grab a bite or go
grab a bite to eat. So
a bite can be a noun,
like a thing, like a piece of food that
you eat, but it can also be a verb to bite.
Like, you know, the dog bites
the man. And so you have to be
careful with this one.
In this case, it's a noun.
Okay, very good. And
well, she wanted to first
go to the store and she said,
"I want to pick up a few things.
" Well, usually when
you pick something
up, you take it from a
table or from the ground.
But in this case, it
means to buy something
because you can't just
pick something up in a
store and then walk
away. You have to pay for it.
Right. So for example,
you can say, "When you
come home, can you
pick up a carton of milk?"
So that means, "Can you buy
some milk on your way home?
" It doesn't mean, "Can
you take some from
someone else or steal
some?" Exactly. All right.
So to pick something
up to buy to go and get,
but obviously you
have to pay. All right.
And he used this very
interesting phrase when
she was getting all these things for her.
She said, "Whoa, whoa, whoa. Are you nuts?"
Okay. So nuts is the important word here.
It means crazy or out of your mind.
That's right. So it's
another way of saying crazy.
So if you call someone
nuts or you say,
"He's nuts," that means.
Yeah. Like, don't talk to him.
He's nuts. Or he always says
really dangerous things. He's nuts.
So he's a little bit crazy.
So it's an adjective as to
describe someone that's a little bit
crazy or a little bit adventurous maybe.
But in this case, he's not actually saying
she's a crazy person. He's saying, "Listen,
this is so much
stuff. Are you crazy?
" Or he's basically saying,
"Do you really want to do this?
This seems like a
bad decision." Exactly.
So that's why he used
the phrase, "Are you nuts?"
Okay. So a lot of
great stuff there.
Why don't we go back,
listen to our dialogue
for the last time, and
we'll be back in a bit.
I'm hungry. Let's
go grab a bite to eat.
Yeah, me too. Oh, can we
stop at the shop really fast?
I lost my makeup bag
at the airport and I want
to pick up a few things.
Will you take long?
No. Five minutes. I promise.
Come on. You've been
here for almost an hour.
I thought you said you're
only going to get a few things.
How long does it
take you to pick out
a lipstick and some nail
polish? Are you crazy?
You have no idea what you're talking about.
Just for my eyes, I have to get eyeliner
an eyelash curler, eyeshadow,
an eyebrow pencil, and mascara.
Then I need to get foundation,
liquid foundation. Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Are you nuts? How much
is all this going to cost?
I'm looking at the price
of each one of these
little things and it's outrageous.
This is basically a crayon.
What about you? You spend as much
money or more on your razors after shave,
cologne, and gel. Not
to mention how much you
spent on clothes. Fine.
Get the stupid $30 crayon.
All right. So talking about
makeup, a lot of things
here, maybe I didn't
mention a couple of things.
I don't know. We took a
look at the most important
things, I think, right?
But you also mentioned
something, for example, cover-up. There's
something such makeup called cover-up.
Yeah. So cover-up, it could be a couple of
different things in English. For example,
something that you wear
to cover your body when
you're at the beach. You
know, you don't want to
walk around and everyone
can see you in your bathing suit.
But when we're talking
about makeup, a cover-up
cover-up is a thing that
we use to hide blemishes
or zits or pimples. So
you know when you get a
really small red dot
on your face and you're
embarrassed and it's ugly and
you don't want anyone to see it.
Well, cover-up is a kind of makeup
you use that looks like your skin color
and you put it on top and
you can't see the red anymore.
Okay. So you
cover-up your pimple.
Yeah. Or you use cover-up.
It's a noun too. Okay.
And I've also seen that,
well, many girls don't
really wear too much
lipstick anymore nowadays.
They use this thing called
lip gloss. Okay, lip gloss.
Remember we were
talking about polish earlier?
Well, gloss is a similar
word. It means something
that makes another thing
shiny. And so lipstick can
be very dry, can be
very flat, can be very flat.
But lip gloss is something
that makes things look
wet, makes things
look shiny. Okay.
And actually one last thing
before when we talked about gel,
I guess guys use gel, but women
use this thing called moose.
Or they could use gel too.
I don't think it's gender specific,
but a lot of people use moose.
I know some men
who use moose as well,
moose is kind of like a
foam. You know, it comes
in a can and it goes,
"fshh." Yeah, and it inflates
this white substance. Yeah,
it looks like, I don't know,
like whipped cream.
Like whipped cream, yeah,
and you put it in your
hair and it's very fluffy
and it's actually less
strong. It's not like gel
because if you put it in your
hair, your hair won't look hard.
But it will help shape your hair if you
want to keep your hair in one place.
A lot of things here.
I think in beauty and
cosmetics, we have a
lot of a lot of things and
probably we didn't
even touch on half of the
things that are out
there. So if you have any
questions or if you want to ask us anything
at all about this lesson or anything else,
you could always come to englishpot.com and
leave your questions and comments there.
So we'll see you at englishpot
and until next time, bye!